Kranti CH

Pre-Doctoral Fellow

Pre-doctoral researcher, developing low-resource language tools for Telugu (Indian Regional) Language. Worked in Industry for 15 years across ML, Digital Payments, and Multimedia domains. Led the team that developed lightweight on-device neural models to enhance soft keyboard experience for Samsung Smartphones & Smartwatches.



Research Work

- Sonal Kumari, Vibhav Agarwal, Bharath C, Kranti CH, Harshavardhana, Sourav Ghosh, Barath Raj KR: A Lightweight On-Device Sequence Tagger using Multitask Learning, IEEE - ICSC 2021 Conference (doi: 10.1109/ICSC50631.2021.00007)
- Vibhav Agarwal, Sourav Ghosh, Kranti CH, Bharath C, Sonal Kumari, Harshavardhana, Barath Raj KR: EmpLite: A Lightweight Sequence Labelling Model for Emphasis Annotation of Short Texts, Joint NLP Modelling for Conversational Al at ICON-2020 Conference (url: https://aclanthology.org/2020.icon-workshop.3/)



Education

May 2021 -Current

Fatima Al-Fihri Pre-Doctoral Fellow

A fellow of Fatima Al-Fihri Fellowship 2021

June 2018 - Oct 2018

Advanced Certification in AI/ML

IIIT – Hyderabad, Grade: Excellent

Dec 2008 - Dec 2010

MS Software Systems

Birla Institute of Technology - Pilani, CGPA: 6.5

Sept 2004 - Feb 2005

PG Diploma: Embedded Systems

June 2000 -

Apr 2004

Centre for Advanced Computing - Trivendrum, Grade: A+

B.Tech: Electronics & Communications

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University – Hyderabad, Percentage: 73%



Work History

June 2007 - Apr 2021

Staff Engineer

Samsuna R&D India, Banaalore

- 3 Patents (Content Generation, Boostina Typina Experience, Multi-linaua) Suggestions] are provisionally filled and full applications are in processing
- Designed and deployed new features for Samsung Soft Keyboard using NLP and Deep Learning Techniques (OTP Extraction, Real-time Emoji Suggestions, Spell Checker, On-Device training)
- Lead and mentored 10+ member team to manage product development, beta releases and commercial deployment for soft keyboard features.
- Delivered Samsung Pay UPI solution for Indian Digital Payments (One of the first UPI solutions in Indian Market) and Spain Digital Payments in collaboration with Obertur, Gemalto and La Caixa teams (Using Embedded Secure Element, One of its first)
- Instrumental in ISDB-T, ISDB-Tmm based Mobile TV stack development for Japan market smart phones

Mar 2005 -June 2007

Sr. Engineer

Tata Elxsi Ltd, Bangalore

- Design and Development of DVB-T Set top box middleware stack
- Re-designed test suite for DTV middleware stack



Contact

Address

Bangalore, Karnataka, India, 560048

Phone

+91-9844726744

E-mail

kranti.ch@amail.com



- C; C++; Java; Python.
- Pytorch
- Android; Tizen; Linux; SHP.
- Product design and development



Honours and **Awards**

- Business contribution award for successful deployment of ISDB-Tmm stack, resulted in 2Mn USD savings
- Super Saver award for royalty saving of 1Mn USD (7\$/phone) for ISDB-T stack development
- Multiple times Employee of the month award, Perfectionist, Nipun Best Demo, TechGlanz Best Demo for the tech contributions at org level



Volunteering

- Women tech club, Samsung R&D
- Social Volunteer at COLING-2020, NAACL-2021
- Poster reviewer and Scholarship reviewer committees at Grace Hopper Conference(s)